Where do you have it written Yes, that you can start
Где у вас написано Да что можно начинать
your own Show me in the Constitution or in the
сво Покажи мне в Конституции или в
legislation the concept of a special
законодательстве понятие специальное
military operation No, it is illegal I
военная операция Нет она незаконна Я
looked through your legislation I am a lawyer
просмотрел ваше законодательство Я юрист
by education your legislation does
по образованию у вас в законодательстве
not have the concept of a special military operation
нет понятия специальная военная операция
there is a counter-terrorist operation Yes, there
есть контртеррористическая операция Да
is no special military operation Hello
нет Здравствуй
German  flag Hello yes Let's have a
немецкий флаг Привет да Давайте сегодня
normal conversation today I'm in the mood Let's
у меня есть настроение С вами нормально
discuss what your interview
поговорить обсудим что интервью вашего
or what or Why No we'll discuss today
или что или Зачем Нет мы обсудим сегодня
Yes today I want to discuss the attack on the
Да сегодня хочу обсудить удар по
oil depot in Engels Did you see
нефтебазе в Энгельсе Вы видели
today at the strategic airfield of
сегодня на стратегическом аэродроме
strategic aviation Ukraine launched a
стратегической авиации Украина нанесла
drone attack on the oil depot
беспилотниками удар по нефтебазе горит
the whole is burning  day repeated explosions How
целый день повторные взрывы Как так
is it that in the third year of its
получается что на третьем году сво
Ukraine takes out your strategic
Украина выносит ваши стратегические
airfields Well, that's how it turns out It's impossible to
аэродромы Ну вот так получается Всё
shoot everything down
сбить
You take it out every
невозможно У вас же выносит это каждый
day We didn't get stuck on this attention
день мы на этом внимании не
How did it happen that is, it
застряли как так получилось то есть это
was part of Putin's plan demilitarization of the
входило в план Путина демилитаризация
Russian Federation
Российской Федерации
put  A normal
ставь Нормальный
question, was it part of Putin's plan that
вопрос входило ли в план Путина то что
the territory of Russia would be shelled like that
территорию России будут Так обстреливать
as a result, naturally
в результате сво естественно
No, he miscalculated, well where As they say
Нет просчитался ну где Как говорится
Yes, and  why are you changing flags
Да а почему ты флаги меняешь
That's what it is blue then
Вот то это жто блакитный то
American now Germany
американский теперь Неметчина
decide not yesterday was Estonia
определиться не вчера была Эстония
the day before yesterday Latvia then Lithuania was we
позавчера Латвия потом Литва была мы
do on the stream lags of different countries
делаем на стриме лаги разных стран
that support Ukraine we don't see
которые поддерживают Украину не видим
anything bad in this
ничего в этом
Germans support Ukraine Yes they
плохого немцы поддерживают Украину Да
support Ukraine It's probably only
поддерживают Украину Это наверно только
there one
там один
Scholz ordinary Germans
шольц немцы рядовые вас
twisted you where where did you watch the survey of ordinary Germans
вертели где где вы опрос рядовых немцев
Let's say Shari has a video let's watch
Давай допустим у шари ролик посмотрим у
Shari No watch another one Shari is not an authority for you
шария Нет смотрите ещё шари для тебя не
No what kind of video is there there is
авторитет Да не что за ролик там есть
just some one German or whoever
просто какой-то один Немец или кто кого
he asks that You say All  Germans,
он спрашивает Вот вы говорите Все немцы
for example, if we see a German on a video
вот если например мы увидим на ролике
who says that you are an elephant, will it
немца который говорит что вы слон Будет
mean that all Germans consider you a
ли означать что Все немцы считают вас
slab, what is the rating of Scholz and now
сло чего рейтинг шольц и сейчас
below NTU and he
ниже нту и он
leaves obs because in
уходит обс из-за того что в
democratic countries it is somehow
демократических странах так как-то
accepted that rulers are annoying  people and
принято что правители надоедают людям и
they change you can't understand this
они меняются у вам это не понять потому
because you don't have rotation of governments
что у вас нету ротации правительств у
you will suffer you will be in terms We are
вас будете терпеть вы будете термы Нам
lucky We are lucky that's lucky and  the Germans are
повезло Нам повезло вот повезло а немцам
luckier they have democracy they
повезло больше у них есть демократия они
can influence their governments and
могут влиять на свои правительства и
parties including Yes they are watching and
партии в том числе Да смотрят а
Ur is falling Rennie is being replaced the same thing
Ур падает Ренни менят его также
with
само у
Ruth now Ultra is right Who Yes
рут сейчас вот Ультра права Кто
no business lips so those don't
Да не дела губки так те не
go with you just A Yes I don't care
идт вами просто А Да мне всё равно
I would be here I'm just saying but don't
Я бы зде Я просто говорю но не
get distracted burn and here
отвлекайтесь гори и вот
and their opponents said and we won't
и их оппоненты сказали а мы вам не
make you an opposition this is firstly and
сделаем оппозицию это во-первых а
secondly
во-вторых
about the
о
irremovability of
несменяемости
power in Democratic Germany
власти в Демократической Германии
how long
сколько там
was Merkel in
была Меркель у
power how long was she elected
власти сколько она она избиралась
elected Yes we have  also elected
избиралась Да у нас так же избирается
electoral you have a little not how long she
избира у вас немножко не сколько она
was in power Merkel was not
была у власти Меркель не была
president they have their
президентом у них у них
president secondary who was Merkel
президент вторичная кем была Меркель
chancellor since the chancellor is elected
канцлер так как избирается канцлер в
how long she was in power how is she elected
сколько она была у власти как избирается
how long would she be how is the chancellor elected
сколько она бы как избирается канцлер
again how is the chancellor elected  how long
ещё раз как избирается канцлер сколько
was she how is the chancellor elected Well, what are
она была как избирается канцлер Ну что
you moving out by whom Tell me by whom is the
ты съезжаешь кем Скажи кем избирается
chancellor elected Yes to
канцлер Да
me Well, if you figure it out, if
мне Ну так вот если разберёшь вот если
so if not your country then
так если не твоя страна так
those authorities 18 years  so Okay how she
те власти 18 лет так Окей как она
was elected
избиралась
I don't know it's not my people people
не знаю это не моя люди люди на каждых
voted for parties at every election and parties
выборах голосовали За партии и партии
that they gained in different proportions they
которые набирали они в разных пропорциях
gained formed a coalition Yes because that's
набирали формировали коалицию Да потому
how it works yes democracy in
что так работает да демократия в
parliamentary or parliamentary-
парламентских или парламентско
presidential
президентских
states took a coalition and the coalition
государствах брали коалицию и коалиция
was elected people
избиралась народа
demos and  red Well here we need to
демос и крас Ну тут надо
add one more thing the power of the American
ещ добавить одно власть американского
people Well then And why exactly the power of the
народа Ну а тогда А почему именно власть
American But look Let's say
американского А вот смотри Вот допустим
this year And no this year nothing
те вот этот год А нет этот год нече не
happened here two years ago let's take Georgia
было вот два чет год да возьмём Грузию
Let's take Moldova there
Да возьмём Молдову там
Russia won the elections  Putin intervened intervened
выборах Россия вмешалась Путин вмешался
these are the former this is the
это эти бывшие это
Georgian president said we did not find
грузинская президент сказала мы не нашли
Russia's intervention but this is the main this is
вмешательство России но и это основной
what is
это как
it This is the main evidence that she
его Это основное доказательство что она
interfered I did not understand what the
вмешивалась Я не понял причём вообще
states had to do with it the
штаты тут
people of Georgia chose for themselves the states did not
народ Грузии выбрал себе штатам не
like the wrong one they chose in Hungary
понравилось не того выбрали в Венгрии
they chose the wrong one  we need to cancel the PPP in Romania
выбрали не того надо отменить в Румынии
that Hungary cancelled that the States
ППП что Венгрии отменили что штаты
cancelled Hungary I didn't understand the elections the elections in
отменили венг Я не понял выборы выборы
Hungary were cancelled the States and Hungary where is there
Венгрии отменили штаты и венгри где там
in Bulgaria I confuse Dava Veri in Bori
в Болгарии я у я путаю Дава вери в Бори
Well where
Ну где
and did they change the elections either in Hungary or in
а меняли выборы или в Венгрии или в
Bulgaria I don't remember in Hungary or in Bulgaria
Болгарии ни в Венгрии ни в Болгарии не
that they would cancel them nearby in
припомни чтобы отменяли бы рядом в в
some country in Austria maybe not
какой-то стране в Австрии может нет
Montenegro no no in the big country
Черногории нет нет в большой стране
Turkey  Eastern
Турция Восточной
Eastern Well look Well what the hell I don't know
восточны Ну поищи Ну что блин я не знаю
I'll
буду я
look for you know Find I don't know where the
искать кра знаешь Найди я не знаю где
states cancelled the elections you're there Hungary
штаты отменили выборы ты там то Венгрия
then Bulgaria what will you come up with Well come on
то Болгария что ты придумаешь А ну давай
find where the states cancelled the
найди где штаты отменили
elections And how I wonder how the states
выборы И как Интересно как штаты
cancelled the election
отменили выбор
Let's do it  you went to the
Давай се на телефоне ты ж полез на
phone you wanted to look And what
телефоне ты хотел посмотреть А что
because you're leaking there is no such thing
потому что сливаешь нету такого
Yes there is such thing you know where Well then answer
Да есть такое знаешь где Ну так ответь
for your words where the states cancelled the elections
за свои слова где отменили штаты выборы
You know this is not the best not me I
Ты знаешь это не лучшим не уже меня Я
have no idea where the states are I'm
понятия не имею где тут штаты Я тебе
serious You  I said so, come on, tell me
серьёзно Ты же сказал так давай скажи
where the states cancelled the elections, I'm
где штаты отменили выборы
interested. I won't even google it, there are
интересно Да даже вот не буду гуглить
half a thousand people watching me right now at the
вот меня полтысячи людей вот сейчас в
beginning of the stream, we're all interested in
начале стрима смотрят нам интересно всем
where the states cancelled them.  elections there in Romania
где штаты отменили выборы там в Румынии
or in Bulgaria or in this Macedonia
или в Болгарии или в этой Македонии
in short or in Hungary or in Austria in
короче или в Венгрии или в Австрии в
Slovakia
Словакии
come on well somewhere there somewhere how they
давай ну где-то там где-то как они
cancelled illegally how they didn't How how
отменили незаконно как они не Как как
they cancelled pressed the button elections in Hungary
они отме нажали кнопку выборы в Венгрии
or how I just didn't  I can understand
или как Я просто не могу понять
earlier how Yes, easily, well, how
ране как Да запросто ну как
Explain the same way they made your Maidan
Объясни так же как они у вас Майдан
explain how in that country how in
сделали обясни как в той стране как в
that country which you cannot name
той стране которую ты не можешь назвать
you cancelled the
ты отменили
election how explain they brought this button
выбо как объясни привезли это кнопку
like canceling the elections they pressed how
типа отмены выборов нажали
easy ctr Z they pressed there or  I
запросто ctr Z там нажали или
don't understand, come on, answer for your words.
не понимаю давай ты ответь за свои слова
You said everything I
Ты сказал всё
understand. No, you're playing now. You
понима Нет это ты сейчас играешь Ты
said that the States cancelled the elections in
сказал что штаты отменили выборы в
Hungary. I'm saying, in which Hungary
Венгрии Я говорю В какой Венгрии даже
don't even remember the elections? Hungary, in your
выборов не пом угорщина по-вашему
opinion, Hungary, there were no elections there
угорщина Ну угорщина не было там выборов
even this year. Well, Hungary,  or somewhere there
даже в этом году ну или где-то там вот
nearby and in Bulgaria too no well where are the states
рядом и в Болгарии тоже не ну где штаты
No no no no Hungary is Orban yes
Нет нет нет нетт Венгрия это орбан да
No not there means no Oh woke up so
Нет не там значит нет О проснулся так
let's where did the states cancel the elections what
давай то где штаты отменили выборы что
you were making it up as you went along I didn't
ты придумывал на ходу я ничего не
make anything up
придумывал
come on where were the elections in
давай где были выборы в двадцать
1924 Let's look for
году Давайте поищем
English Wikipedia opened for me
английскую мне открыл
strangely accustoms you to the Great
странно приучает вас к Великому
English language already
английскому языку уже
in
в
Bulgaria in Bulgaria Read where in
Болгарии в Болгарии Прочитай где это в
Bulgaria the elections were cancelled
Болгарии отменили
supposedly not this one won how did you
выборы там выиграл якобы не этот как его
read it not  find Alice Find
прочита не найди У Алисы Найди
ssi what kind of elections were in Bulgaria
сси какие какие выборы в Болгарии были
look when the elections were in Bulgaria
посмотри когда выборы были в Болгарии
no Read there was no there was No you are not
нет Прочитай не было не было Нет не ты
deceiving You have deceived for the second time now Come
обманываешь Ты вот сейчас второй раз
on When were the elections in
обманул Давай Когда были выборы в
Bulgaria
Болгарии
last year look when and what
в прошлом году посмотри когда и какие
Come on Why No Yes  you lied there were no
Давай Зачем Нет Да ты обманул не было
cancellations of the elections there were no cancellations
там никаких отмен выборов не было Вот
Really Ask Alice if the
реально Спроси у Алисы отменили ли
elections in Bulgaria were cancelled in two fourths Come on,
выборы в Болгарии в два четвёртом давай
ask for the fifth time I say I won't from
спроси в пятый раз говорю не буду от Вот
Look because no you read and you
смотри потому что нет ты прочитал и ты
made it
придумал
up Look you asked Alice I looked at the
Смотри ты спросил У Алисы посмотрел
list  and said the word Bulgaria I
список и сказал слово Болгария Я
remembered Well I'm
вспомнил Ну я
not a country but I'm asking it you're asking it's very
не страну но я же её ты спрашиваю очень
simple just ask  now Alisa has
просто вот спроси сейчас У Алисы
cancelled the elections in Bulgaria in the
отменили ли в Болгарии выборы в дца
fourth year here is just
четвёртом году вот просто
really the results of the elections in Bulgaria in the
реально итоги выборов в Болгарии в
twenty-fourth year
двадцать четвёртом году
now
сейчас
we will find the charts charts
найдём графики графики
some bad link nothing is clear
какая-то плохая ссылка ничего неясно
ngari there were difficulties after cheno
нгари возникли сложности после чено
Bulgaria on the elections of Bulgaria the coalition won
Болгарии на выбора Болгарии победила
[music]
[музыка]
will be found the
найдется
Supreme Court  page
ВС страница
[laughter]
[смех]
unavailable in page unavailable no Here is the
недоступна в страница недоступ нет Вот
first
первая
constitutional court of Bulgaria opened a
конституционный суд Болгарии возбудил
case on partial cancellation of elections that's
дело о частичной отмене выборов вот о
what I was
чём я и
talking about in parliament in
говорил в парламенте в
Bulgaria they demanded cancellation of elections there and
Болгарии требовали отмены выборов там и
resignation of the government Well and
отставки правительства Ну и
such where elections were cancelled elections
такое где отменили выборы выборы
came Look you didn't cancel Read
пришли Смотри не отменили вы Прочитай
so Read where they cancelled Find where they
так Прочитай где отменили Найди где
cancelled I tell you in Bulgaria there is no
отменили я тебе говорю в Болгарии нет то
what you did not read that they cancelled Read
что ты не прочитал что отменили Прочитай
that they cancelled the elections in
что отменили выборы в
Bulgaria what the constitutional court
Болгарии то что конституционный суд
look the elections took place Yes political
смотри выборы состоялись Да политические
parties can appeal to the
партии могут обращаться в
Constitutional Court it appeals it
Конституционный суд он обращается он
accepts consideration from this elections
принимает рассмотрение от этого выборы
are not  cancelled let's see where the
не аннулируются давай смотри где
elections were cancelled Read that the elections were cancelled in
выборы Прочитай что отменили выборы в
Bulgaria I
Болгарии
won't Well  read Well look you see
не буду Ну прочитай Ну смотри видишь ты
this is the third time I know why
уже третий раз я это знаю зачем
I needed it first in Hungary then
мне сначала это было в Венгрии да потом
it was in Bulgaria then now it
это было в Болгарии потом сейчас это то
turns out in Bulgaria then it turns out in
получается в Болгарии то получается в
Bulgaria the presidential elections were cancelled so it
Болгарии президента отменили выборы так
turns out let it be yes well look at
выходит пусть будет да а ну посмотри
what kind of elections there were  presidential or
какие выборы там были президентские или
parliamentary in Bulgaria let it be don't
парламентские в Болгарии пусть будет не
look
посмотри
look Well, come on we We
посмотри Ну ты давай мы Мы же
agreed We wanted to have a
договорились Мы же захотели серьёзно
serious talk Come on, to have a serious talk,
поговорить Давай чтоб серьёзно говорить
turn on with you
включаешь с тобой
not You look
не Ты смотри ты
you've been trying for 15 minutes already to find what
15 ты 15 минут уже пробуешь найти то что
you said based on the fact that I'm all
ты сказал опираясь на то что я всё знаю
I know I know everything No I don't know that Show me and
я всё знаю Нет я это не знаю Покажи и
your Alice doesn't know and you and Alice
Алиса твоя не знает и ты вместе с Алисой
don't know You and Alice with Alice's help
не знаешь Ты с Алисой с помощью Алисы не
can't find what you came up with I found
можешь найти то что ты придумал Я нашёл
no Read where it says that the
нет Прочитай где там написано что
elections were cancelled yes tell me back  No,
выборы вот да скажи мне обратно Нет так
it doesn't work that way. Prove it back. If you
это не работает Докажи обратно ты если
make a statement, you
де делаешь какое-то утверждение ты его
have to prove it. That's how it
должен доказывать так это
works. Zelensky. I swear, no, no, no.
работает Зеленским Клянусь нет нет нет
Come on, find another one. Find it. Read it.  where is it
Давай найди ещ м Найди Прочитай где
written yes and I will also look at this then
написано да и я тоже посмотрю это тогда
that in Bulgaria the elections were cancelled I Googled
что в Болгарии отменили выборы я Погугли
Yes I did not find that in Bulgaria
Да я не нашёл что в Болгарии отменили
the elections were cancelled Well then it was not cancelled So then
выборы Ну значит не отменили Так значит
I am wrong
я не прав
cheat that's it come on so you admit that you
чит всё давай так ты признаёшь что ты
were wrong Then I am wrong Yes
был не прав Значит я не прав Да
admit it means I'm wrong super so it
признаёшь это значит я не прав супер так
turns out the states didn't cancel the elections in
то получается штаты не отменяли выборы в
Bulgaria it means they didn't cancel super
Болгарии значит не отменяли супер
yes it turns out democracy Yes it's not
да получается демократия Да это не
only for the American people but for
только для американского народа а для
different
разных
peoples for example
народов например
for the Bulgarians for example
для болгаров например
[laughter]
[смех]
Bulgaria holds elections
Болгарии проводят выборы
they choose from them yes And at  you and we are
выбирают у них да А у вас и у на
holding
проводят
elections the election in the nineteenth year And
выборы выбор в девятнадцатом году А у
we have in the past Well, that's right And we have a war
нас в прошлом Ну правильно А у нас Война
going on, so it's impossible for us to hold
идёт поэтому у нас невозможно провести
elections And with whom is it a
выборы А с кем с
war with Russia or our own Yes, we
Россией война или сво Да война у нас
don't have a war our own We
нету сво у нас такого понятия
don't have such a legal concept No, you are Russia  war
юридического Нет вы России войну
declared or M Russia declared war we had martial law we
объявили или М Россия объявила вой у нас
had martial
вели вели военное
law in our we have in our Constitution it is not
положение у нас в у нас в Конституции не
written that the country that attacked
записано что страна на которую напали на
us yes should Declare
нас да должна Объявлять
war You can declare
войну Вы можете объявить
martial law in our  Martial law has been introduced
военный у нас Ведено введено военное
Yes yes Can you announce we have
положение Да да Можете объявить мы
announced for how much m for 3 months and it
объявили на сколько м на 3 месяца и
is extended every 3 months
продлевается каждых 3 месяца
but it cannot be extended because
а его продляется то нельзя потому что
such is the procedure well let's
така такая процедура ну-ка Давай
see let's see let's see let's see
посмотрим давай давай давай посмотрим
Constitution or in the law where it
Конституции или в законе в каком где это
can be extended  I don't know, you don't have
можно продлять Я не знаю нет у вас
such a thing, Putin told us, we
такого тин нам говорил нам Путин говорил
can't
нельзя вести
continue for 3 months or cancel or
на 3 месяца дальше или отменять или
war. Declare where we have no
войну Объявлять где у нас у нас нету
obligation to declare war on someone
обязанности Объявлять кому-то войну у
in our Constitution, in our Constitution,
нас в Конституции у у нас в Конституции
in our legislation, there isn't even one.  the concept of
у на законодательстве даже нет понятия
declaring
объявить
war because Ukraine is not
войну потому что Украина ни на кого не
going to attack anyone we don't have such a thing
собирается нападать у нас нету такого
that we owe someone Declare war And
что мы кому-то должны Объявлять войну А
in what
в каком
legislation or do we have this in
законодательстве или у нас это в
some article that we
какой-то статье что мы вот вот войну
declare war then and then and then  no,
объявляем тогда-то тогда-то этого нет
nowhere I I'm not saying I'm not saying
нигде я Я же не говорю Я же не говорю
that you declared war it's you what am I
что вы объявляли войну это вы что я ва
saying your laws it's No you you
говорю ваши законы это Нет вы вы
came up with the idea that someone had to declare
придумали что кто-то надо было объявить
war and
войну и
that's it you here Yes, for example, look at us
всё вы вот Да у нас например смотри у
our current president can go to the
нас действующий президент может пойти на
elections and lose the elections, for example
выборы и проигрывают выборы например
Yushchenko went to the elections and lost, admitted
Ющенко Шёл на выборы проиграл признал Да
Yes, Poroshenko went to the elections and lost,
вот Порошенко пошёл на выборы проиграл
admitted Kuchma, uh, for the third time, did not go for a
признал Кучма ээ третий раз не пошёл на
third term, like Putin, did not go Although
третий срок как Путин не пошёл Хотя мог
he could have been inclined towards Russia, yes, Kravchuk went
его склонялись России да Кравчук пошёл
to the elections and lost everything  honestly we have
на выборы проиграл всё честно у нас есть
democracy we have a rotation of
демократия У нас есть ротация
political parties if people don't like something
политических партий если людям что-то не
yes people elect others and you can't do
да люди избирают других а вы не можете
it
это вы
you we don't need another we don't need yes yes you are
вы нам другой не нужен не нужен да да Вы
all
всё
right cool guy And we
правильно классный чувак А нам вот этот
need this one on the streams cool  Dude, who
на стримах нужен классный чувак а кто
are you or what? No,
это ты что ли
bring it closer to the camera, I don't
Нет поближе камере поднеси кто это не
recognize it, move closer, just to the
узнаю его подвинься поближе просто к
cup, I moved, but you, bring it
чашке я подвинулся но ты камере поднеси
closer to the camera, move closer to the cup,
ты ближе вот сюда к чашке подвинься
who is it, what, can't you
ближе кто это да что не
see? Well, do it like this, move the
видишь ну вот сделай так вот ну
cup closer to the camera  bring it so it's
чашкой поближе камере поднеси так это
so
так само
close move to the camera
близко подвинься к камере
so you can announce once
так вот вы можете объявить один раз
military why not why are you telling us
военны зачем не зачем вы нам говорить
what can we do one Where did you get the idea that we
что мы можем один С чего вы взяли что мы
can do one time you can't do it where is it
можем один раз не можете его где такое
written that we can't extend it anywhere
написано что мы не можем продлить нигде
not and more I'll tell you where you have it written
не а больше я скажу где у вас написано
Yes what can you start your own Show me in the
Да что можно начинать сво Покажи мне в
Constitution or in the legislation
Конституции или в законодательстве
the concept of a special military operation  no
понятие специальная военная операция нет
it is illegal I looked through your
она незаконна Я просмотрел ваше
legislation I am a lawyer by education
законодательство Я юрист по образованию
your legislation does not have the concept of a
у вас в законодательстве нет понятия
special military operation there is a
специальное военная операция есть
counter-terrorist operation Yes
контртеррористическая операция Да
special military operation No show
специальной военной операции Нет покажи
me on what basis Putin signed a
мне на каком основании Путин подписал
decree on conducting a special military
указ о проведении специальной военной
operation if
операции если такой операции в
you
законодательстве у вас
do not have such an operation in your legislation  I wanted it so much
нет ему так захотелось
don't wait look again you have a
не подожди ещё раз смотри у вас есть
book there pick it up it's called the
вроде там книжку подними называется
Constitution Do you have legislation
Конституция У вас есть законодательство
Yes which is different another question there is
Да которое другое ещё вопрос там ни
not a word about the concept of a special military
слова нет о понятии специальной военной
operation in what cases In what cases is
операции в каких случаях В каких случаях
it declared Who has the authority to
она объявляется Кто имеет полномочия
introduce that is Putin does not  had the authority to
вводить то есть Путин не имел полномочия
declare a special military operation
Объявлять специальную военную операцию
because there are no powers the powers of the
потому что полномочия нет полномочия
president are clearly written into the Constitution
президента чётко вписаны в Конституции
open up what Open up I'll tell you now I'll
открой ка ти какой Открой я тебе сейчас
tell you now the section
скажу сейчас тебе скажу раздел
directly powers now I'll turn it on directly
прям полномочи сейчас я включу прямо
so that I can read I read the powers of the
чтобы я читал Я читал полномочия
president and you  you read
президента и ты читаешь
So we will open the Constitution of the
Так мы прямо сейчас откроем Конституцию
Russian Federation right now here on the
Российской Федерации вот на сайте
official website chapter four probably Now
официальном глава четыре наверно Сейчас
I will say for sure chapter four article Yeah
я скажу точно глава четыре статья Угу
eightieth will
восьмидесятый пойдёт
probably go to load me
наверное меня подгрузить
now Well yes chapter 4 because chapter p
сейчас Ну да глава 4 потому что глава п
is already the Federal Assembly
это уже Федеральное собрание
now why do you have 2 days already no no  no don't
сечас кчему у вас уже 2 дня нене не не
say let's not jump from question to
скажи вот давай не прыгаем с вопроса на
question Show me where your powers are in the
вопрос Покажи где у вас полномочия в
Constitution I'm loading I want the
Конституции я я загружаю Я хочу
official website here I have loaded
официальный сайт вот у меня загрузился
like this chapter tyre article 893 Yes chapter 4
так глава тыре статьи 893 Да глава 4
President of the Russian
Президент Российской
Federation become article
федераци стать статья
8093 find me
8093 найди там мне
powers there Kai sta because  that they are all
полномочия Кай ста потому что они все
big articles
большие статьи
I'm asking you Find at least one
Я же тебя спрашиваю Найди хоть в одной
article they are not there in any article they
статье их нету там ни в одной статье
are not there Here I take So it means that it is not
нету Вот я беру Так значит это что не
prohibited no no no no no not like that not like that No no
запрещено нет нет нет нет нет не так не
it's not like that not like that it works
так Нет нет это не так не так работает
not like that  work I will explain to you as a
не так работа Я я объясню тебе как
person with a legal education for a
человек с юридическим образованием для
citizen everything that is not prohibited is
гражданина всё что не запрещено то
permitted For an official the
разрешено Для чиновника действует
opposite principle applies only what He is
обратный принцип только то что Ему
allowed to do and that is what he can do yes that
разрешено что он и может делать да то
is  an official,
есть чиновнику
uh, he is given certain
ээ он наделяется определёнными
powers that are clearly spelled out
полномочиями которые чётко выписываются
in the legislation, that's the trick, that
в законодательстве вот в чём фишка то
is, an official, for example, of this
есть чиновнику например ээ этой
customs service, no, it doesn't say that he is
таможенной службы Да не пишется что ему
prohibited from stopping cars at
запрещено останавливать автомобили на
intersections. Yes, as a policeman, he
перекрёстках Да как полицейскому он это
can't do this, only a policeman
не может делать только полицейскому
is written that he can stop a
написано что он может останавливать
car  yes, that's how it is,
автомобиль шнику да вот так что так вот
that's how the powers of officials
так полномочия чиновников Чётко
are clearly spelled out and they cannot go beyond the
прописываются и они не могут выходить за
limits of their powers for a citizen,
пределы своих полномочий для гражданина
what is not prohibited is permitted.
действует что не запрещено то разрешено
For an official, only what is
Для чиновника действует только то что
permitted is permitted, so look,
разрешено то и разрешено так вот смотри
look, article 80, so there is no occurrence by the head of
смотрим статья 80 так так главой
state  81 article
государства нету проис 81 статья
is elected no so 82 no 83
избирается нету так 82 нету 83
so appoints the State Duma has the right to
так назначает Госдуму имеет право
accept no right svoe no no
принимать нету пра сво нету нету
forms the Security Council Vo form that's it
формирует Совет Безопасности Во форми
forms that way 84 the president of the
вот вот формирует так 84 президент
Russian Federation appoints elections
Российской Федерации назначает выборы
dissolves a referendum addresses the
распускает референдум обращается к
federal assembly that's it water PTA
федеральному собранию так воде ПТА
article no
статья нету
neck that's it conducts negotiations signs
шея так ведёт переговоры подписывает
there is no certificate of acceptance, so here is the seventh article
нету статья так вот во седьма статья
look, that's right, the president of the
смотри как раз правильно президент
Russian Federation is the supreme
Российской Федерации является верховным
commander-in-chief of the Armed Forces of the
главнокомандующим Вооружённых силами
Russian Federation, in the event of aggression
Российской Федерации в случае агрессии
against the Russian Federation or an
против Российской Федерации или
immediate threat of aggression, the
непосредственной угрозы агрессии
president of the Russian Federation introduces martial law on
президент Российской Федерации вводит на
the territory of the Russian Federation or in
территории Российской Федерации или
its individual areas,
отдельных её местностях военное
so that's what he
положение так вот то есть что у него
has in his powers - this is  introduce martial
есть в полномочиях - это ввести военное
law on the territory of the Russian
положение на территории Российской
Federation if there is a threat so here is the
Федерации если угроза так вот режим
martial law regime manifested by the
военного положения проявляется
Federal Constitution and law so
Федеральным конститу ци законом так 8
Article 8 no just nothing
статья нету прос ничего
Article 9 so citizenship everything no
статья так гражданство всё нету
ninety no ninety-first no ninety-second
девяноста нету девяносто первое
no ninety-
нету девяносто вторая нету девяносто
third no that is it turns out the
третья нет то есть получается
only
единственные
powers of the president in the Constitution
полномочия президента в Конституции
on these military issues Yes, this is the
по военным вот этим вопросам Да это
introduction of martial law, the
введение военного положе
introduction of martial law on the
введение военного положения на
territory of the Russian Federation in the event of
территории Российской Федерации в случае
aggression against the Russian Federation,
агрессии против Российской Федерации у
we dont have it anywhere. Thats right. Thats right. Im
нас его нету нигде Вот вот да Так я же
telling you, Im not talking about that. Im saying that
тебе говорю я же не про это Я говорю что
my concept of a special military operation
сво понятие специальная военная операция
in  your legislation No I
в вашем законодательстве Нет я с 22 года
went in and looked at 22 where it says
зашёл и посмотрел где ж написано
special military operation what is
специальная военная операция что это
it What body is authorized to do it
такое Какой орган уполномочен её делать
either the President or  at the instigation of
либо это Президент либо с подачи
the president, the Supreme Council, your
президента Верховный Совет ваша там
gift Duma, who is not there, that is, a
дарственная Дума кто нету то есть
special military operation - this is an
специальная военная операция - это
illegal
незаконная
event signed by Putin, uh, through
мероприятие подписанное Путиным ээ через
exceeding his powers, he does not have these
превышение своих полномочий у него этих
powers, so he does not have them in court against us, so
полномочи поте на нас в суд нет так ещё
look again Wait, stop, we are now
раз смотри Подожди стоп мы сейчас
talking about justice, are you there?  about
говорим про справедливость ты там про
Legality you were tugging at this there, it
Законность ты там дёргал этим то
turns out that your president of the
получается что у вас президент
Russian Federation went beyond the boundaries of
Российской Федерации вышел за границы
his powers and signed a decree on
своих полномочий и подписал указ о
some incomprehensible procedure that
какой-то непонятной процедуре которой
is not in your legislation, I
нет у вас в законодательстве я правильно
understand correctly, but yes, let it be so In ninety-
понимаю а вот да пусть В девяносто
four he led the regime Who in Chechnya  It
четвёртом он вёл режим Кто в Чечне Это
was also illegal In ninety-
незаконно тоже было В девяносто
four he was not
четвёртом он не был
president Well, but in 2004 Sorry Sorry
президентом Да ну а в 2004 Извини Извини
yes misspoke
да оговорился
misspoke regime here I am
оговорился режим вот я же я же тебе
telling you that the regime of the counter-terrorist
говорю что режим контртеррористической
operation You have I told you so I
операции У вас есть Я же тебе и сказал я
told you so but in your ATO  also yes
так и сказал а вот в вашей ато тоже есть
yes again again look again again
да ещё раз ещё раз смотри ещё раз ещё
again stop stop stop stop look you
ещё раз стоп стоп стоп стоп смотри у вас
have a concept of counter-terrorist operation
контртеррористическая операция есть
Yes and a special military
понятие Да а специальная военная
operation on the territory of another
операция на территории другого
you don't have such a concept of the state it
государства такого понятия у вас нет
turns out now there is no no Show me
получается теперь есть нету нету Покажи
where Show me where there is a law yes about a
где Покажи где есть закон да о
special military operation and we
специальной военной операции а он нам
need it Well you have to decide
нужен Ну вы должны определиться что
what a special military operation is
такое специальна военая операция
who about don't run away don't run away now don't
кто о не убегай не убегай теперь не
leak we look we're not talking about it now  the court
сливай мы смотри мы сейчас не про суд
we are talking anyway Yes according to the law
говорим мы говорим всё-таки Да по закон
or not the law you wanted to present me with what there is the Constitution
или не закон ты мне что там Конституция
martial law
военно положение хотел мне предъявить
here I am presenting you with a special
вот я тебе предъявляют специальная
military operation Yes this is an event
военная операция Да это мероприятие
that
которое
was
саво
proclaimed by Vladimir Putin the
провозглашено Владимиром Путиным
President of the Russian Federation who did
Президентом Российской Федерации который
not have the authority to do this that is this
не имел на это полномочий то есть этот
man Security Council was going to
человек Совет Безопасности собирался
probably sa no Where where means together with the
наверно са нет Где где значит вместе с
Security Council he illegally
советом безопасности он незаконно
signed this is not in the Constitution Show
подписал это нету в Конституции Покажи
here Security Council let's open it
вот Совет Безопасности давай откроем у
we have an open Constitution let's see
нас же открыта Конституция посмотрим
if there is a section in the powers of the Security Council
есть в полномочиях Совета Безопасности
so there is no section Security Council in the
так нету раздела Совет Безопасности в
Constitution
Конституции
yes Yes there is for example Federal  meeting
да Да есть например Федеральное собрание
government Well, where is there no, you know,
правительство Да ну где нету понимаешь
no, you don't have a
нету у
special military operation, no one
вас специально военной операции никто её
can declare it. This means that we
не может объявить Это значит что мы на
didn't attack you. No, this means that
вас не нападали Нет это значит что
you. The
вы вас
Russian Federation has an article for
Российской Федерации есть статья за
unleashing  aggressive war Now I will
развязывание агрессивной войны Сейчас я
read you aggressive war and war
вам прочитаю агрессивной войны а война
can still be non-
ещё может быть не
aggressive Well,
агрессивная Ну
ask your lawmakers this is what your your
во спросите у своих зако это же ваши
your deputies came up with Now I will
ваши ваши депутаты придумали Сейчас я
read you in aggressive war this is how it is written
прочитаю во агрессивно вой так и
in your Criminal Code this is how it is written in your Criminal
вас так написано в вашем Уголовном
Code Article 353 planning  So
кодексе 353 статья планирование Так
now we now it to
сейчас мы сейчас оно
load 353 planning preparation of
подгрузить 353 планирование подготовка
unleashing or waging an aggressive
развязывания или ведения агрессивной
war Punishable by imprisonment for a
войны Наказывается лишением свободы На
term of from se to 15 years that is citizen
срок от се до 15 лет то есть гражданин
Yes citizen Putin Vladimir Vladimirovich
Да гражданин Путин Владимир Владимирович
committed a
совершил
crime under the Criminal Code of the Russian Federation article 353
преступление по УКРФ статье 353
planning preparation once the commander
планирование подготовка раз командующий
unleashed what powers did he have
развязаны какие у него были полномочия
to
на
unleash  You see, there is, there is, he
развязывание Вот видишь есть есть
untied Yes, he
развязал Да
untied there is And what did he do no Now
развязал есть А что он сделал нет Вот
if you
если бы у вас
had, Now if you had, look, if you
было Вот если бы смотри если бы у вас в
had in your law, if you had in your law the
законе было если бы у вас в законе было
concept of yours, then what is yours, who is
понятие сво тогда бы и что есть сво кто
authorized to announce with then  if only it were
уполномочен оглашать с тогда бы это было
so you don't have your own regime your own is not
так у вас сво нету режим сво не
defined by law so it
определен законодательно так это есть
only exists in your media heads so as
только в ваших медийных головах для того
not to call the war a war  against
чтобы войну не называть войной против
another state to call a word Yes this
другого государства называть сло Да это
is a war this is an aggressive war
есть война это есть агрессивная война
this is a Crime this is a
это есть Преступление это есть
crime Yes According to the Criminal
преступление Да Согласно Уголовного
Code of the Russian Federation Yes and more
кодекса Российской Федерации Да и больше
Yes you you are also like you are a person you are
Да вы вы также как вот вы человек вы
because this war yes You should also
потому что эту войну да Вы также должны
be like this is  Russians will be
быть как это по-русски притягнути
brought to justice Yes, according to the
привлечены к ответственности Да по
Criminal Code of the Russian Federation
Уголовному кодексу Российской Федерации
Yes, when the Russian volunteer corps
Да когда русский добровольческий корпус
enters the Kremlin Yes, the power of the VK will change
войдёт в Кремль Да поменяется власть ВК
Everyone like you Yes, it will be necessary to find and
всех Таких как вы Да нужно будет найти и
bring to justice all those who
привлечь к ответственности всех кто
supported the war against Ukraine for years,
годами поддерживали войну против Украины
the murder of people in Ukraine, everyone must
убийство людей в Украине все должны
bear the burden
понести
I will say more about legal responsibility
ную юридическую ответственность я больше
in Israel there are services that
в Израиле есть службы которые
catch those who during the
отлавливают тех которые ещё во время
Second World War Yes, they destroyed
Второй мировой войны Да уничтожали
Jews SPO itself is the destruction of Jews and
евреев СПО собст уничтожению евреев и
holds them accountable and
привлекает их к ответственности и
Ukraine Yes, after Ukraine's victory,
Украина Да после победы Украины будет
such a headquarters will be created it will be called the
создан такой штаб он будет называться
headquarters of justice that will look for
штаб справедливости который будет искать
everyone  People like you who
всех Таких как вы людей которые
supported the aggressive war against
поддерживали агрессивную войну против
Ukraine Yes, you too I personally will be I personally
Украины Да вы тоже я лично буду я лично
Yes, I will be present at
Да буду присутствовать на судебном
your trial Personally, I will
процессе над вами Лично я
come Wherever it takes place I
приеду Где бы он не проходил я вам
tell you I will come here we will make this
говорю я приеду вот мы мы сделаем этот
process quite  public with broadcast
процесс довольно публичным с трансляцией
on YouTube in chat roulette so that you
в YouTube в чат рулетку для того чтобы
know how it will be Nuremberg
знаете как вот это будет нюрберг
2 you you will be small there but
2 вы вы там будете маленькая но
I will do Especially for you I will make
я сделаю Специально для вас я сделаю
such a wide
такую широкую
broadcast also now I have turned on the
трансляцию ещ тоже сейчас включил вам
sound for you you can talk and I was without sound or
звук можете поговорить а я был без звука
what A  there is something there is something to say in your
ли А есть что есть что сказать в своё
defense Andryushka I'm waiting for
оправдание Андрюшка жду
you look it turns out yes let's
тебя посмотри получается да
summarize you admitted that after all
резюмируем вы признали что вс-таки
there is democracy in other countries
демократия в других странах есть
No I didn't admit it don't interrupt you admitted
Нет не признавал не перебивайте вы
that you didn't
признали что не
admit it you admitted that you deliberately
признавал вы признали что вы сознательно
lied
лгали
that the US cancelled the elections in Hungary then
что США отменила выборы в Венгрии потом
you  admitted that you deliberately lied that the
вы признали что вы сознательно лгали что
US cancelled the elections in Bulgaria then you
США отменила выборы в Болгарии потом вы
admitted that Vladimir Putin is a
признали что Владимир Путин есть
criminal who unleashed an
преступником который развязал
aggressive war you admitted that in
ээ агрессивную войну вы признали что в
your legislation
вашем законодательстве
there is no such thing as a special
Нет такого понятия как специальная
legal operation and the President of the
юридическая операция и у президента
Russian Federation does not have
Российской Федерации нету
the authority to declare such a
полномочий ээ Объявлять такую
special military
специальную военную
operation  I
операцию Я вас
congratulate you And I'm done Can I
поздравляю А всё закончил можно звук-то
turn on the sound for you now Can I turn it on
теперь тебя включать Можно да включил
Yeah Now I can
Угу Теперь я могу
talk and now you turn off the sound for me
говорить а теперь ты мне Звук
Andryushka like that  conversations are not
выключи Андрюшка так разговоры Не
built such a drain
строится такой слив
you to me Turn on the sound Well and I will turn it off for you
ты мне Звук включи Ну и я тебе выключу
then
тогда опять
again I'm waiting for the trial right now you will be mine and the
же жду на суд прям вот будешь моим и
judge and why
судьёй и чом
did you turn it on again
включил опять
silent no Sound is on I hear You
молчит нет Звук включен я слышу Ты чашку
take a cup Why are you lying that you are silent That
берёшь Зачем обманываешь что молчишь Что
my sound is turned off
звук у меня выключен
You me  do you hear
Ты меня слышишь
no now what do you want from me
нет сейчас ты что от меня хочешь
[laughter]
[смех]
we destroyed grandfather with arguments at the
мы аргументами уничтожили деда ещё в
end just like that you
конце просто так
know highly intellectually
знаете высоко интеллектуально
mocked You shut up
поиздевались Ты молчи
copy write to y Telegram right now axis VN
ко пись на й Telegram прям зараз ось ВН
and
а
pok ce very and very important YouTube is busy with
пок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through the SRG ORV in yours  ban and very
нас через срг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
many videos I don't show to people sometimes I don't
багато вдео не показую людям вчасно не
show information about streams so
показуе информация про стримы тому для
that we Mali promptly
того щоб ми Мали оперативный звязок
write links right now and while there in telegram OKM videos
пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в телегра
there is also interesting and useful
окм вдео ще теж цикава и корисна
information and we apologize to you constantly
информация и ми повинни з вами тримати
operational linkage
постийний оперативный звязок
independent in that chi will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
subscribe and
подпишись а